hello and welcome it's October 31st
2024 we're in active guest stream number
90.1 and Benjamin Nelson will be
presenting And discussing mechanics of
the mind so Benjamin thank you to
you good morning um today I uh would
like to discuss uh the development and
integration of various cogn cognitive
mechanisms within a unified framework I
have been developing um um I am
currently competing for the uh in
the-art competition and I'd like to talk
about um the framework I've designed um
to emulate human uh cognitive functions
and enable Advanced decision-making uh
most importantly abstract reasoning in
computational systems um I'd like to
start uh of course by introducing
several mechanisms I've designed uh each
contributing uniquely to the system's
overall functionality um um in
pre-testing these the combination of
these mechanisms which I won't be able
to get into all of them today
unfortunately because I've been uh
competing for the arc rise and it's
incredibly challenging and uh and
transformative is amazing so um but um
these the combination of these
mechanisms have uh in pre-testing uh so
far uh scored U consistently above 85%
which is uh uh really encouraging and um
I will be submitting uh here shortly so
um the mechanisms we see um I have
listed here is uh attentional selection
memory encoding and retrieval
reinforcement learning uh distress
Dynamics which is uh much like uh
emotions in the system um and somatic
stress uh those underlying stresses that
uh uh kind of fuel uh those emotions
right um the Epsilon control uh
prioritization optimization iteration
belief Dynamics and adaptation and uh
very importantly uh Robert warden's uh
requirement equation uh it's the
requirement for cognition in an equation
here uh reshaped uh uh to create a like
a representational efficiency um as a
subsystem that's woven throughout uh the
cognitive Computing framework um within
this framework um and for the purpose of
uh this presentation I have categorized
um these functions into somatic and
autonomic uh processes and um I want to
talk about
um briefly like kind of what that means
so um one of my
like my favorite thing about active
inference I would say the people or the
the amazing amount of democratized
Education or um The Innovation or I mean
there's just so much right but one of my
favorite favorite things is the ability
to uh take these ideas using the high
road and low road to active inference
and pull them out of the out of just
nothing out of the ethos out of our
thoughts and our conversations and turn
them into uh something that has
substance it's tangible and
um in doing so I've uh I've come across
some really amazing things I'm excited
about new papers that I'll be writing
later this year so um
the attentional selection like memory en
coding uh and retrieval uh reinforcement
learning belief adaptation
prioritization optimization iteration
these conscious process processes um are
reflective of
uh cognitive functions but there's there
isn't a onetoone relationship between
these things these are uh
representations these are confabulations
of mine and how I uh see these processes
um where it's more important for uh the
outcome uh to be the same as opposed to
um the processes to exactly mirror uh
biological functions so um we also have
uh subconscious uh operations in the
system uh such as uh distress um and
somatic stress um uh Epsilon control the
the uh it's amazing in these processes
many of them do not work unless there is
entropy uh and then of course uh belief
Dynamics and adaptation um we see uh
resource allocation in this balance and
interaction that occurs between these
processes or autonomic functions manage
Baseline operations freeing sematic
functions for higher level tasks one of
the things that started me down this
road years ago uh was an attempt to
resolve cognitive feedback loops in
people like to understand them and to um
see if there was some way to um either
circumnavigate or circumvent these types
of Loops in
conversation uh it was the first time
that I applied a mathematical framework
to a philosophical problem or a
syllogism um and uh in doing so I I kind
of opened the door for myself um to that
eventually led me to he to active
inference in The Institute so um these
things deal with uh in the framework
resource allocation so uh autonomic
functions will manage those Baseline
operations as I said the feedback Loops
those autonomic functions provide inputs
to the somatic functions for example the
distress Dynamics which um I'll go into
more here in a little bit um which for
instance could influence attention and
many other things um the um well I'll
get to that in a second I get ahead of
myself so um the
uh as we see here the we require active
processing and deliberate control these
functions involve conscious decision-
making processes where the system
actively selects stores updates and
refines information based on current
goals and evidence uh autonomic
functions operate uh without the need
for a conscious intervention um distress
Dynamics as and these other U mechanisms
we discussed fall into this category
they manage the systems internal States
and beliefs based on ongoing input so
for instance in the arc prise the uh the
tasks the grid tasks that are presented
um and uh the purpose being to ensure
stability and adaptability in response
to changing conditions which is uh
necessary um and uh kind of a an
intrinsic property of of these Dynamic
States so um one of my favorite things
that I have learned through this uh is
about the role of uh marov arrays so uh
The marov Matrix uh that uh
is modeling the probabilistic effects of
stress on cognitive functions and state
state transitions um in this very simple
uh illustration here um we can see them
as uh unique and separate layers that
are passing values up and down if we
were to you know stack them uh passing
values up and down and the the reporting
from those uh rows columns uh informs
the for instance the Epsilon control
distress stes belief Dynamics uh the
warden's a requirement equation the
subsystem um they're to take a massive
amount of data tens of thousands of
arguments uh methods and calls and send
them uh in a very nonlinear fashion
through the system um to dynamically
influence every part of the system
simultaneously so um that the entirety
of the system is in play and acting
simultaneously um and we'll talk a
little bit more about how that works
momentarily um here when we look at this
is an older illustration so I apologize
um but it um displays something that I
really that I think is really kind of
cool how the cognitive landscape and a
cognitive Computing framework can be
visualized so when we see these um uh
like our internal and external model and
the information is coming in then these
marov arrays are passing information
back and forth there updating those
States and and uh predicting those State
Transitions and um through that like for
instance if we include memory encoding
and retrieval and we were to treat um
these spaces on those grids uh in the
same way as nodes like a file folder
with compress data there are groupings
of those data over time through
iterative processes that uh strengthen
those beliefs uh for instance like prior
beliefs so as there is more and more
confirmation uh evidence
those uh nodes for all intents and
purposes are assigned higher order
values and those higher order values are
uh passed through that system um and
yeah I think it's really to balance um
what would be a uh internal model and an
external model
the the predictive capacity I I'm really
excited about researching this more too
because the um with one or two the
the uh probabilistic effects uh and on
like uh cognitive function State
transitions it's um it can be inaccurate
uh which is okay it's it's not meant to
be perfect uh in that way um but when
you put many of them together that uh
the accuracy of those predictions and
the um the like the temporal element to
those predictions uh and that accuracy
increases exponentially so I'm excited
about exploring that more certainly so
um the um these components that are in
this system that are communicating and
carrying information uh or that how
these marov uh arrays are carrying
information nonlinearly through the
system uh from these uh cognitive
mechanisms and all their components
um
uh operate synchronously and
asynchronously um it's really really
fascinating there's this there's just a
continuous stream of of uh simultaneous
data blowing throughout the entire
system the arrays effectively serve as
like conduits for data flow within the
system um con interconnecting everything
and allowing everything to operate
independently and meaningfully um which
is controlled through the Epsilon
control so um these
uh probabilistic like the the arrays
handling the probabilistic transitions
between different cognitive States uh
effectively ensure the entire system is
dynamic and we get real time uh
information processing it's really
really fascinating um the uh with the
inclusion of Robert warden's requirement
equation the uh that the efficiency the
the amount of energy required for the uh
the amount of computation that occurs is
um significantly reduced it's amazing um
so
uh Central to the nonlinear
communication really is like a dynamic
State transition model Pro like uh model
probabilities of moving between states
based on internal and external factors
and there you know the uh in data
propagation where we're facilitating
data flow between these mechanisms so
they enable these complex interactions
ensuring that changes in one mechanism
appropriately affect another so um
the next slide here we kind of see how
that works a little bit where the
distress calculation um which is by the
way so uh this is one of my favorite
things right so when coding in Python
which I'm not a software engineer uh or
an expert by any means um and uh
competing in the arc has been one of the
most challenging experiences in my life
it's really really fun um the these
these equations uh translate uh really
really well into Python and give a
framework for the ideas that um I have
about the way that um emotions would
would be represented in computational
systems the way that uh evolutionary
imperatives would be represented in a
system the way that um uh subconscious
processes would be represented in the
system so uh you can there's like kind
of like an unlimited amount of
creativity the with python as uh your
medium you can almost do anything it
seem seemingly do anything it's it's
really really really incredible and um
what uh uh an interesting and bizarre
form of self-expression I never knew uh
that I would engage in it's just
absolutely wonderful so we see that the
distress calculation is regulating the
distress it's updating distress States
we see uh coefficients at play these uh
individual arguments representative of
things like the derivative of time right
or contextual factors um external
stimulus um and those are updated there
is uh the somatic stress system
that
is understanding the the role the impact
of motions and guiding the system
through um by adjusting things like the
cognitive load time pressure for
instance when you're taking a test this
is specifically for the arc prize which
has a time limit so um there's Focus
intensity for like intentional uh
tensional selection when focusing on uh
grid tasks and prioritizing what part of
that Grid or feature of that grid is
important and needs to be understood um
having errors and error feedback uh very
important right uh how resources are
distributed through the system and
something I'm really excited to talk
about later on which demonstrates I
think um kind of the flexibility of this
in terms of how kind of fun and silly it
can be and simple and then of course uh
we'll talk about how incredibly
brilliant and Powerful it can be um uh
seen in uh the warden RI subsystem um
the marov array that you see in the
middle that's how I've made them in the
system and you see um different
arguments feeding into that array with
uh predetermined values those values uh
can be tuned uh which is really amazing
it's uh the the fine-tuning the system
is one of the funnest things that uh I
do because when the when the nature of
the the project changes or the
application is different the system can
very easily be fine-tuned to best meet
the uh requirements for that uh task or
object or you know undertaking so um
with Robert warden's requirement
equation in the system it maximizes the
efficiency of those processes um greatly
so um before I move on to that here I
wanted to um talk a little bit about
Robert warden's requirement equation um
which is designed uh in this way to
maximize the overall Fitness by guiding
decision-making so um for the uh purpose
of the arc test so in Fitness evaluation
it effectively assesses outcomes of
actions incredibly flexible uh decision
guidance recommending actions that
maximize Fitness and it integrates with
other systems such as prioritization
optimization and iteration to uh provide
optimization criteria um within the
marov array it um adds that uh um
Dynamic compute expected uh Fitness
values which uh influen decisions across
the across the entirety of the system um
the uh let's see here I want to talk
about um something really kind of fun
because the uh before we talk about some
things uh you know in terms of like uh
uh why these things are important and
what they could potentially mean uh in
terms uh of our future right and how
these um new intelligence systems uh
emerge so the I actually worked on this
with a friend of mine who's a carpenter
he's uh he makes cabinets and and uh I
uh I've known him for years he was my
boss when I was a just a kid he was kind
of my first mentor and away and he's
still a close and and dear friend of
mine uh 30 years later and uh we were
talking about how do we how do we
understand um like how would we approach
decisionmaking and how would what are
some things that in decision making that
we would think valuable and for me it
was like kind of my confidence and
whether I'm right or wrong I can't
really know um especially if it's
something that I've never seen before
and that's kind of the basis of uh uh
Fran chol's uh Arc prize and the arc
test is that uh he wrote a book called
on the measure of intelligence and in
that book The he talks about how the the
way to really solve like a problem to be
an abstract Problem Solver is too the
problem uh with no knowledge of a
solution no knowledge of the problem and
to be able to solve it so in that way uh
for me it's a the the only way I could
kind of finalize my decision is in terms
of my confidence that I'm right or wrong
and when we look at turning that into a
computational framework is really pretty
simple as you can see it's um uh you
know am I right am I wrong what's my
initial confidence right is probably
going to be relatively low but as I as I
move through the task and I feel like
I'm doing well and my emotions are calm
and um I you know like uh my beliefs
about this based on what I've done so
far are confirming that the things look
right um my vision uh is telling me that
it looks good and that uh that's what
it's supposed to look like and all of
those things through uh those Markov
arrays are feeding this confidence and
increasing or decreasing these values
and that initial confidence effectively
goes to the point where uh you're so
confident in the decision that
you just go hey I've solved the problem
right so the model says Hey I've hit uh
you know
0996 I'm convinced that this is okay so
I initially thought that uh the
confidence uh if it was right it would
be high and if it was wrong it would be
low uh and that is not necessarily the
case at all in fact the confidence that
uh a confidence or an understanding that
you may be wrong should just be uh
slightly less than being right and um uh
what happens uh in the model is that
when it's solving these tasks that it
becomes overly confident it was amazing
the system becomes uh effectively
arrogant and starts just making
decisions on what it thinks whether or
not it thinks tasks have been resolved
and I was not really sure what to do um
I thought that the the mechanism just
might not be effective or that um I may
not have uh uh developed it correctly um
it was my dear friend um that I just
mentioned who uh noticed that and
commented to the to the point that when
people are arrogant or when something is
uh overly confident it is uh humility
that um resets that stage and it was
then that I applied a a Decay Factor
again the role of entropy in these
systems I applied a Decay factor to
reduce that confidence when uh over time
and in response to uh answering
questions correctly to to uh reduce that
so it it's approaching each new question
with uh with a fresh mind without making
assumptions about uh uh what's whether
or not it's right or wrong the answer so
um I thought that was really funny and
there's a threshold for understanding
when the the system should stop and we
see that um down below as the confidence
threshold which is uh just a fraction of
a point um I don't know if I got that
right there are things that I just kind
of like uh copied and pasted out of uh
different code segments from different
uh iterations of this uh uh process so
um uh conversely something that's uh
really really really amazing that is
very
similar but um much more serious in
terms of its impact is the requirement
for cognition and equation in a
computational framework it seems to
represent uh to be representative of uh
almost like a representational
efficiency it it manages that Fitness
throughout the system um
by kind of controlling the flow of
energy and how where energy is
distributed in the system and why that's
important um it's calculating those
State Transitions and making predictions
about those things and informing the
rest of the system so the the amount and
I would encourage everybody to explore
um the this as um something that is so
far incredibly flexible and improves
everything that it touches it's uh I
really can't uh overstate how valuable
that this has been in being able to
produce meaningful results around uh the
cognitive Computing Frameworks that I've
been uh attempting to develop so uh for
instance uh when when I Incorporated
distress Dynamics emotional attenuation
into the system um curiosity uh
happiness and the the component pieces
which I didn't have I do have uh uh
visualizations on but I I didn't have a
chance to incorporate them this morning
so U my apologies um but if anybody's
interested please reach out to me and I
can show you what those wonderful things
look like uh where you can see not just
the emotions modulating through the
system uh over iterations but you see
their components the of those emotions
uh modulating through those systems as
well um and not necessarily in in tandem
it's uh it's pretty pretty amazing so um
the let's see where was
I so when I Incorporated the distress
Dynamics into the um the arc model
called the Archangel which I actually
named after uh Daniel fredman because he
is uh definitely um uh an angel to me
and uh
the the the percentage of correct uh
questions the correct predictions about
the output grid uh and being reflective
of you know an input Grid or a training
example anything like that uh test that
went up by 30% right um I could not get
above the theoretical maximum of
85% uh
without Robert warden's requirement
equation no matter how much I
complexified
the uh the overall uh or individual
mechanisms or the overall framework so
um to the point of you know more than
doubling the uh amount of just code
that's in the system complexifying these
mechanisms um and just to see if that
would necessarily be the case and uh
fascinating and uh and uh
um drives my curiosity certainly um that
was the case so um the effect that the
requirement equation for instance has on
prioritization iteration uh optimization
and iteration like op uh optimization
within the system um increased my score
exponentially so the effect that it has
not just as a in itself but the role it
plays in influencing the Effectiveness
and efficiency of all of the other me
mechanisms in the system uh created like
an aggregate increase that was uh as
significant um as uh as those of the
distress Dynamics um the more it it
seems to be that Simplicity is really
the key um with the arc contest in some
ways that um the the more you add in the
the like the more kind of like I guess
the you know it gets computationally
like muddy and uh it it seems to be
difficult for the model to embrace like
the end to move quickly through uh
relatively what would be simple tasks
for uh you know you and I um the using
just simple form and uncomplex form like
non-complex forms of these cognitive
mechanisms by you know using the
equations threadpool uh for
parallelization and things like that um
speeds up that process and makes the
model much much much more effective to
the tune of U in some cases solving
tasks within for smaller grids within uh
one to two uh or three iterations it's
very interesting to see a cognitive
Computing framework get an answer right
on the first try um and to see that in
real time is really cool and to to have
had a part in making that it's like it's
amazing so um the there's still like
there's so much to do I'm really excited
about um submitting um at the arc priz
and the opportunities that that may hold
and I am excited about many of the the
discoveries that uh were kind of
emergent uh phenomena it's I don't when
I think of coding I think of
deterministic systems and maybe you do
too of of there not being um any
autonomy or um abstract action it's it's
everything is dictated it's prescribed
and the seeing uh this model operating
in that system and making these
decisions in these ways where it kind of
it gets to take off on its own and its
own beliefs about those things dictate
what actions it chooses right so when we
like reinforcement learning you know our
thoughts uh our experiences our past
experiences those inform our beliefs um
and our along with our uh you know what
we're inferring or foraging right um
those beliefs uh inform our actions and
those actions have consequences and in
that you see the the beginnings of I
think like what would be considered
almost like a cognitive trajectory and
uh it's going to be really fun to
continue to um explore and complexify
those things and um look deeper into
them and and see what can be found so um
the I apologize in some ways I didn't
have the opportunity to uh prepare as
much as I would have liked I've actually
never done this before so um I'm really
really thrilled to be here uh and to
share even a little bit or to contribute
in some small way and I hope that um uh
my work uh as it as it gets better and I
continue um at The Institute learning
from all of the great and amazing minds
of Scholars there um and the amazing
access to resources that they have that
um I'll be able to gauge uh more
meaningfully and have opportunities like
this again in the future and I hope that
uh if you uh find any of this
interesting that you reach out to me
directly and uh I can have uh more
detailed conversations and answer
questions and things like
that thank
you all right
for those watching live they can write
questions let's go over what the arc
challenge is you didn't show any grids
or anything so not everyone may be
familiar so could you show any
pictures or the code running or what the
arc challenge is and walk us through
what the system is doing what is the arc
task how do cognitive mechanisms relate
to what is being done for the arc task
well that's really exciting so um I'm
happy to go into that so um I'm a little
hesitant to run code uh and I'm a little
hesitant to interact with my computer
too much so I have a very old laptop um
and just show some images then just go
to a website where we can see some
examples and talk us through how the
mechanisms relate to it fantastic okay
give me just a moment
all
right all right and should I I imagine I
should stop sharing and then just
reshare this screen here okay me just a
moment yes so uh this is the arc prize
leaderboards where I hope to be uh soon
um and this these are there are over a
thousand teams of the most brilliant
people uh around the world uh competing
for what is uh called The Arc prize and
the arc is the abstract reasoning Corpus
it is a way to test computational models
on their ability to think abstractly and
to solve problems uh to Sol for abstract
problem solving right so um when the
uh model is uh and here I'll leave that
so it when the model is uh engaging with
the tasks it's presented a series of
grids and there are patterns colors um R
things that need to be done as you can
see in this case here there there needs
to be one uh yellow field here there
it's F it's filled in and you see these
as they become gradually filled in this
would be like an example of what the
model would encounter in training data
in in the training phase and then as you
see the last one uh it would say oh okay
well obviously I need to fill in empty
space with the yellow squares right uh
and um that becomes much much much more
complex over time uh through the test as
I understand it uh when I let me see if
I can go here here and uh yeah I've we
this is like because humans can take
this too um and my score right now in
pre- testing is about the same as a
human so about 86 to I think 88% is
about what uh a person would score um
taking the arc so um the you can see
here where a just simple pattern
completion the grids range anywhere from
1 by one to 30 by 30 um as stated here
uh on the arc website the I can only
imagine um that the patterns uh
presented in such large grids become
really complex I and though you can't
see what the model is doing you there
are certain things you can see like the
computational load like through kaggle
uh where the contest is hosted uh you
can see the performance of your system
and also I can hear my computer uh as
it's starts uh sounding like a jet
engine going off as it's like trying to
you know process and uh this model so um
the uh Arc test as I I think I mentioned
was uh created by uh and co-founded by
uh franois cholle um who's also the
founder of Caris and guys just
absolutely brilliant I've learned a lot
about them since I've been here and um
let me see here now um if I
can pull up an example of my framework
and Daniel if you'll let me know um if
whether or not it actually shows up
because this is where um the my computer
typically wants to start slowing down
okay so you can see there um I one of
the most difficult things that I have
encountered for the this entire uh
process was the actual generation of the
submission old ER itself uh there is um
as I might have mentioned I'm not a
software engineer by any standards and
it uh it can uh there is a lot of really
highly technical um and uh see here
beautiful version uh a lot of Highly
technical things and for um brilliant
and like experienced innovators and
leaders like uh the folks at mindes I um
probably not even a hurdle uh but for me
it was like a really really really
difficult process and I was able to get
uh some help from a very brilliant
gentleman and I finally uh was able to
generate the um the submission file so
now I can I had to tear my model apart
to figure out where it was going wrong
and then I was able to now I can put it
back together and actually submit so um
wonderful here um can you see the
Daniel fantastic so um very boring stuff
that's just the Imports um the the model
doesn't use the Internet it's not
allowed to use the internet um because
the test answers need to be uh you know
they they got to stay secure so um the
everything that the model does is is
internal you have small things that you
you know like you know pandas or
whatever that uh libraries that you
access but those are things that um the
wonderful people uh behind kaggle have
already loaded and are available in the
system for you so um that's really
wonderful as part of the notebook so um
here um to start you can see there's a
combination of two different types of of
um uh kind of like uh Frameworks right
so there's you know how we have like
machine learning and then there's all
these other stuff right and then you get
down uh to the to the newest one and
that's active inference so but active
inference on its own for something like
this is not necessarily effective
especially given the time constraints
that I've been uh under having only
started and found out about this uh
about six weeks ago so um I've included
some uh in this process some
functionality that is uh more akin to
just physical processes like the ability
to interact with the objects as if they
were physical so there's um uh
dimensionality reduction and other uh
like for instance feature extraction and
um uh different types of tools really um
that the model can imploy uh to help um
navigate and manage those processes so
um here we'll see uh prioritization
optimization and iteration as an
algorithm uh in the
the process and what this is doing is
performing perceptual gating by
Computing the dot product as you see
between the input data and the beliefs
so the arguments that we're seeing is
that the input data so that's the input
sensory data and the agent beliefs are
going to return the Gated perceptual
output so um when we look at that
obviously that's not enough on its own
so it's like how do we how do we round
out these product make each mechanism
holistic right I think of it like a
circle with circles inside of it
um and you know the more you can fill
that operation that overarching
mechanism will and complexify it the
more effective it will be in some ways
right there's obviously a balance but
then you have Robert warden's
requirement equation comes into um to
drive that efficiency and balance that
throughout the system so you get you can
get away with a lot so um we calculate
the optimization objective is a ukian
norm between desired and actual outputs
again you can see the arguments um there
and uh these were really fun gradient
calculations which um I was able to uh
uh based on some uh fluid dynamics uh
some maths that I learned from Keith
affis um I was able to create gradient
calculations that use dimensionality
reduction to to um calculate uh a two
like a two-dimensional space in a
onedimensional space and it was uh
really cool and we get um basically a
waiting system like a more complex
waiting system in a simpler environment
um so we have weight with respect to the
optimization objective and we have
weight with respect to um uh noise in
the system and reducing uh noise and um
I I'm sure many of you are aware that
computational noise in systems is
something that slows the process causes
mistakes um and so uh yeah
there's a um we when we're going to uh
see here where we're defining the the
the algorithm uh and we're implementing
it we get uh the input sensory data we
get the agent beliefs our noise
parameter the target output the maximum
number of iterations and the convergence
tolerance right very important things so
um convergence in these systems is um
kind of the where all of the things come
together and they agree on the task and
the confidence hits that Mark of saying
this is now I know it's right and then
it the model will submit the answer kind
of like the short and sweet to that um
and then um here back this is uh this is
just simply some processing um I don't
know what the grids are and I don't know
what they look like and I don't know
what um like people have done so
uh I and I don't think anybody does I
haven't actually talked to anybody else
uh who's taking who's competing in the
ark but um for instance what if there
are multiple layers and there are colors
hidden underneath the layers right so um
I for a
time had um the had given the model uh
the ability to um assess the grids four
dimensionality and if necessary Vis like
visualize them in two and
threedimensional
spaces um to find out if in fact that
was the case and then return um that uh
to the fun other functions we'll see
that scale the Grid or resize it um
things like that here we have our
attentional selection uh just our simple
attention mechanisms um we're using uh
uh feature dimensions and hidden
Dimensions um much like we would with uh
beliefs um really fun stuff really
simple um nothing too exciting there now
the hot field Network how the memory
works is actually really fun and I've
had a super exciting time playing with
this I mean and maybe um you know I
might have even taken it too far and
almost like destroyed my own computer um
hot field Network's uh amazingly dynamic
in this case um the uh memory en coding
and retrieval between the hopfield
network which works uh under the
Atkinson shiffer model of memory so we
have like a long-term short-term working
memory and this hot field network is
expanding within that as it is absorbing
data collecting patterns things like
that and uh employing a heian uh uh
equation for that encoding and retrieval
and that's been very very effective and
it's opened doors to uh some ways to
manipulate the hot field Network um that
again you have to be really careful with
because the you know you might uh
accidentally set your computer on fire
um so the the things here it's a little
dense and I don't know what my time
constraints are so I'm going to move
past that for now but um I have uh
written a research paper um that's uh
you can find on my link tree uh about
this specifically and I I go into much
more detail um the memory system and
capacity you can see the capacity the
size of the hot field Network these are
all defined things you know the hot
field Network is the Hop field Network
size the memory is done in a deck form
where the each Max Lan uh Max will be uh
you know a a number of decks so a Max
Lin is 10 decks right so we're going to
have whatever that Max Len is that's our
that's going to be our capacity of the
the total deck so um uh here we see how
uh kind of a cool uh condens refactor of
a complex encoding mechan M and a lot of
uh a lot of like Tri accept blocks
things like that to uh handle um uh
errors in the system things like that
keep it going so here we go you can see
um the long-term memory which is not
really at play in this system it's I
haven't really engaged it I don't know
if really if it's necessary even because
of the way the the hot field Network in
this system uh will expand and contract
it's Dynamic to meet the needs of the
task I wanted to I didn't want to come
in with a memory system that is just
holding uh all of this training data and
um has like a a really strong prior
knowledge of what the tasks are I wanted
to kind of stay true to Francois Chet's
as I interpreted um uh perspectives on
uh problem abstract problem solving and
I want the model to uh use and Leverage
it's the the full weight of its
cognitive mechanisms to solve the
problem uh in that way as if it had
never seen it before and was unaware of
it and a solution but can still uh
abstractly resolve the the issue so um
you can also see the size of those uh
memory systems um and uh I we passed it
already I didn't touch on it but there's
also um you know like the amount of
beliefs that can be held um in the
memory systems and I guess I can um
touch on this as well the normally this
uh there's a much more complex framework
that's my actual cognitive Computing
framework that I have deconstructed uh
and decomposed and reconstructed to make
Archangel for the arc prize um but
that's that physical memory which is uh
partitioned into drives is uh short-term
long-term and working uh is set up as a
uh as a system of nodes and like data is
grouped through these encoding processes
and retrieval processes it's influenced
by belief and emotions um like much like
uh a hot field Network would be and how
memory is I'm sure we all can identify
with that and those uh there are
iterative processes that continue to
organize and to strengthen that as new
information new data comes in um to form
priors and to assist with the formation
of uh um uh posterior beliefs uh and uh
in regard to New Evidence uh which we
see ties in through that same Marian
process uh into uh belief into beliefs
yeah so um those higher order values
that are produced when that uh when the
new uh information comes in or uh like
data is grouped more tightly together uh
and compressed into those uh those notes
those higher order values are reported
um as uh assumptions about the world
things that the model would need a
certain amount of evidence to uh
override and to change uh its thoughts
uh in regards to that so it's not
something that uh that you know that you
have to impose on the system in terms of
like uh saying if in an if that this if
this then that relationship it is uh it
is automatic it it modulates itself and
um it's really cool to see it's really
fun to watch and uh I have an like a
natural language processing version of
this cognitive Computing framework for
you know so I can interact with it have
response generation and uh um in that is
where you see how those memory that
memory system is incredibly effective
for um producing uh subtle nuance and
contextual data so um the somatic system
that you see here this is where we see
kind of like the the if we were just to
distill down like what is happening in
the system like you would in a body it's
we would look to like uh or I would look
to my uh my thoughts and my feelings but
my feelings in a subjective way but this
deals with those physical processes that
are happening more so and how energy is
distributed through the system carried
and influenced by emotions or distress
in the system so we have cognitive load
right uh time pressure Focus intensity
error feedback and the limitations of
resources and how those impact uh
confidence so um we uh see that we can
adjust uh stress levels uh based on uh
all kinds of things including task
difficulty um how those uh stress levels
are managed and in that maravian process
when for instance let's say um I uh
encounter a task or the model encounters
a task I should say and it gets the
answer wrong and there will be a
redistribution of resources through that
system and also uh in synchronously um a
redirection of the cognitive load away
from
uh uh functions that aren't in play or
as necessary to uh and kind of Guided by
Robert Ward's requirement equation to
try to maximally like uh put the system
to the task I should say so uh here we
have the Epsilon control uh which uh I'm
a really big fan of and this is like
kind of where we can fine-tune those
processes um and uh under
like create a system here uh for the
them to operate autonomously so they
there's like automatic they can
automatically modulate uh and create you
know stability throughout the system um
when things get really Dynamic you can
also manually fine-tune these things but
uh here you can see the application of
the marov Matrix and its role there um
in uh uh catching that distress vector
and updating those distress levels and
of course again entropy in the system
applying Decay so um the cognitive
system class that you see now um is kind
of where all of these things come
together uh in and
like
in not so much to solve the task but for
the the like a homogenization of uh of
all of these uh necessary oper ation so
for instance we see now um the all of
those many arguments that come together
to form what emotions are in the system
we see uh three um represented here
happiness anxiety and curiosity which I
thought would be uh the best for
resolving the tasks and of course the
that that stimuli when we are happy it's
reward we have anxiety we feel a penalty
and the difference between or the not
maybe the opposite but counter to
curiosity would be novelty right um and
uh when we are propagating C cognitive
States through that marov Matrix to
communicate those things to homogenize
all of those things we're going to see
the influence of those emotional states
on the Markov transition probabilities
for how does anxiety affect the system
how does it affect decision-making how
does happiness influence decision-making
these processes are happening uh
synchronously and asynchronously so the
that is a a massive like uh uh spread
throughout the system um you know
looking at those processes H or those um
uh mechanisms as like you know uh little
circles with circles inside of them
throughout all of those things are woven
these threads of of distress that um
influence and the
uh all of the functions as those
cognitive states are propagated um
through the marov Matrix so um we get to
introduce nonlinearity by applying uh
nonlinear transformation here I'm I'm
sure uh many of you are probably more uh
familiar with uh sigmoid um and cogno I
believe and uh tan uh which something
I've been learning about it's very very
amazing um tan is obviously my favorite
and I think uh because um as Daniel uh
has uh told me many of times it's not uh
to stop engaging in
Hyperbole and I'm working on it very
much so so um now we see some uh action
selection so simple just action
selection um the evaluating our actions
um where we see um The marov Matrix um
in
play for
um the how like itive states are moving
through the system and and we're going
to assign like rewards and penalties
which I basically just picked up from Q
learning uh features and for
reinforcement learning so there I'm just
kind of taking what I can know and
taking what I have what I think will
work and trying it so certainly getting
uh uh consistently above
86% um in on the arc test even I think
in pre-testing um is no small feet the
being able to do that is the culmination
of tens of thousands of failures um I
could I would love to making a composite
of all of the failed code Snippets and
sections and everything that I've like
just kind of that sit in the junk pile
and it's massiv tens of thousands of
lines of code um that have produced from
that um hundreds of lines of code that
are effective in resolving these issues
that um seem to uh as outputs reflect
the outputs of uh biological processes
and cognition so um iteration always
super important update emotions
propagate States select actions evaluate
right um here we see our confidence
scoring class uh is sorry about the
names for some of these things six weeks
of 20 hour days uh seven days a week to
compete in uh one of the hardest uh and
most technologically rigorous uh
competition certainly that I've ever
been in my entire life um and uh but my
dedication and self-determination is uh
is indomitable so I will I will just
work 20 hours a day seven days a week
till I either win or lose uh and
fortunately for me that submission
deadline is rapidly approaching so I'll
be able to sleep for a couple of days
and uh get working on writing wonderful
research papers which is like my
favorite thing you know thinking about
all of the wonderful uh uh mysteries of
active inference
and uh cognition in existence and and
putting those ideas on paper so again
Decay um I actually named this after my
friend his last name is doll so uh I
call it the doll factor to introduce
humility and um uh I as much as I love
him uh he is a very confident person so
uh it uh fitting to uh name humility
after him in this system so um many
people who are familiar with uh active
inference are probably familiar with Q
learning um Q learning is implemented
here as a uh almost like an agent uh is
what I've been calling it but it has um
a really uh a really really really like
uh powerful effect on action selection
um again it's you know the if we are if
our beliefs are informed by our
experiences our knowledge our
assumptions about the world and
ourselves um and our actions are
informed Med by our beliefs uh then
certainly uh re the reinforcement
learning uh which is employing Q
learning here would be uh U would have a
large part to play in that so I I spent
a lot of time the Q loing is also very
very uh for anybody who's interested in
doing this type of thing or finding out
more q- learning is very very very very
touchy it's very sensitive it it it
errors and it breaks and it is uh it is
fragile and and I wonder H not to engage
in hyperbole but how that reflects uh
our memory and our assumptions which for
all intents and purposes are not real so
um uh here we see Robert warden's uh
requirement equation is a subsystem um
the uh uh we're going to get initial
representations of uh and of what's
happening in the system and that's going
to create uh efficiency scores for these
things those efficiency scores are going
to be passed and calculated uh all of
those things exactly as the equation
would which is amazing to be able to um
take something that's so brilliant and
uh
just and that's kind of guess what I was
like meaning when I said that it's like
uh it's flexible it's you can and it
integrates into anything you can just
take the equation itself and and write
it here and then say you know okay so
the sensory input to generate new
representations from decision variable
action variable probability distribution
Over States conditional probability over
decision given State uh the conditional
probability of next state given current
state in action and value function
mapping between states and future States
for our uh parameters and very very very
quickly uh line out uh this these rep
representations these efficiencies and
integrate them into uh so many other
things uh through the uh use of those
marov arrays so or marov Matrix um we
can calculate the representational
efficiency very simply um decision
variable action variable probability
distribu distribution Over States right
value function mapping between State and
future State conditional probability of
next state given Uh current state and
action I mean it's just inedible and we
see these here um in the same way that
you would see
notations uh in uh many of the papers
that I've read uh through the active
inference Institute um and uh we can
calculate Fitness uh in the the system
based on Robert W's requirement equation
um as you see here is a a same thing
decision variable acttion variable
probability distribution Over States on
and on uh the value function mapping
between states and future States so um
here's where we get to to the where
everything both types of uh you know
where we see the kind of the mix of uh
artificial intelligence and cognitive
Computing or at least my attempt at
cognitive Computing um this is where
they come together in the form of like
tools in hand for solving tasks um in
the problem and solving intelligence
class um we uh have our Epsilon our
distress
um I made uh well I'll talk about the
multi-agent plurality um here shortly
but we also see um all of our uh uh
coefficients for the distress Dynamic
calculations those values represented
our marov uh Matrix uh and uh all of
those you know belief history uh somatic
stress confidence um the um weights the
Epsilon control um all of those things
coming into play the distress State
indices such as uh the cognitive load
time pressure Focus intensity um we see
the memory system uh here and we uh are
uh starting to see now uh some actions
and uh things that deal specifically
with the task themselves so for instance
uh something that I found was really
interesting um that uh made an impact in
terms of how many questions I was
getting right was giving the model the
ability to think about how hard the task
was before it started the task and in
this simple uh bit of code here just a
very very simple heuristic we have the
size of the
grid what are things that are unique
about the grid and then
uh return th that those values and uh
pass it along it's and all of a sudden
uh the confidence the the effectiveness
of the confidence in the system uh works
better it's like um the the role of
emotions uh has a greater impact on the
uh generating the correct task output um
the it's hard not to and I'll be honest
with everyone it's hard not to fill this
with as much um map plot lib and logging
and debugging all everything that you
can do because looking inside and seeing
the um just thousands and thousands and
thousands and thousands of uh
contributing forces and factors and
variables at play is so cool and uh um
yeah so it's it's neat to look into uh
inside of these and see how these things
work specifically um when even someone
like me can uh put pen to paper and make
these things without knowing how they
will necessarily operate or work um
calculating rewards extracting features
um reinforcement learning uh and how
those things uh play effect Q value
history um State action pairs
Etc um the I know we're getting to
something I really enjoy here um Fe
extraction selecting actions based on uh
you know the um those return Q values
the higher the Q value uh the the more
often that a uh uh uh The Chosen task
has been correct so it's the model is
going to necessarily try those higher Q
values first since they are the most
likely to be true uh and then move on to
other actions uh including things like
rotating the the grid um looking at it
flipping it horizontally vert vertically
um reducing it um zooming in so uh to
see uh better detail um and uh um here's
the scale grid uh and uh let's see
here uh the generating the action space
so this was a lot of fun to try to
figure out um because I have no idea how
to do any of this stuff it's like how
what even happens when the the model is
in the system this is one of the things
that was so difficult with uh finding
out how to even submit the file is
because the the model is doing all of
the lifting you like we can um interact
with the uh we can interact with the
model on the outside into terms of like
tuning it but once it's inside there you
you can't see what's happening so I'm
generating that action space was uh
really really really uh interesting to
give the agents something to work with
inside that space so and here you can
see um that I had to disable um many of
the trans uh like the Transformations
because they they weren't effective the
they weren't producing um Q values
effectively and they were increasing the
uh the size of the action space so much
that they uh
that they wouldn't meaningfully uh that
like it bogged down the the system
overall computationally so um I uh I
just kind of null those um and here we
see resize grid features um solve grid
tasks with multi-agent support so I
don't know if there's any uh younger
people in the audience um there uh if
there is uh maybe you're familiar with a
um a cartoon show called Naruto and this
character the main character H one of
his his abilities uh they're kind of
like superheroes uh and one of his
abilities is to um become uh to clone
himself to become like a thousand of
himself all at once and he uses that to
overpower his enemies kind of thing um
in this case I wasn't sure if it was
actually even allowed um but I figured I
would uh give it a try the the when we
think about like taking a test I think
about um the dialogue that I will have
with myself and I have one internal
voice like you know that I talk to but
it made me think of uh of that um
dialogue where you see like you know you
have an angel on one shoulder and a
devil on the other shoulder or you know
the Pitchfork guy or whatever it is and
they're having a conversation back and
forth and presenting counterpoints in
different ways of looking at things um
certainly that plurality could be uh
represented computationally and the form
of Agents inside of the agent so when
the agent gets to a point uh where it is
stuck the uh this multi-agent
plurality uh is enacted and these agents
appear um inside of the agent
effectively and they receive their own
test grids and they start trying to
solve the test grid as they look out
through the agent at its test grid and
at the input test grid um when they
can't get an answer right themselves
they do something that this is why I
wasn't sure if it was uh allowed or not
they ask each other they it um here uh
let's see here where is that uh well
well I oh it's up there in the problem
solving class I should have I should
have mentioned it but um up there where
those uh those class those different
thing the functions are instantiated you
see um the number of agents and you can
change the number of Agents you get
could be 100 it could be five I I kept
it very low at I think three to five
agents um and when they get three
answers wrong they they raise their hand
and they hold up their grids and they
say what do you guys have and those
agents communicate with each other as
we'll see in a second where they say oh
I've got this and they go oh okay that
you got that one ahead of me so now I
know what the right answer is and when
the those agents are able to complete a
grid collaboratively that grid is then
passed to uh the model agent Archangel
uh and it's then used or employed to
complete the task so um lot of that was
actually really super fun to make uh I
really enjoyed making that um and I I I
kind of organically and one of the first
things that I ever uh presented to
Daniel and I think I I showed this uh
when I very first came to the Institute
um and uh was was hoping to be led in
the door uh was a schema for um what I
know now is uh colloquially I guess
referred to as a a multi-agent system so
um that uh I haven't gotten a chance to
make one really before and I uh have
made this one and I've gone and uh
further complexified the system uh to
make uh what I've so far been calling uh
nexi which are little uh um little
autonomous uh agents um but uh they are
Builders as opposed to uh and uh as
opposed to
um agents that call out to each other
with greed they don't have greedy
policies
so
um uh so evaluating the solution really
simple it's like for going through the
uh training and evaluation phases um you
you want to know how you're doing this
is a a visualization stuff for me
because I love seeing this it's a values
rewards Epsilon um and uh this is uh
just kind of boring stuff here that's uh
not very much fun um we see um as we're
coming up on training and evaluation uh
spaces um there are certain like
secondary or tertiary cognitive
processes within here uh Within
like the throughout the model so I mean
for instance here you'll see um uh how
we're handling predicted output shapes
mismatching and coming down here to our
selecting our actions but we know that
these this action selection is heavily
influenced by reinforcement learning and
the Q learning feature right so um that
continues um as these things uh uh
further intertwine uh here we go as we
see it the the reinforcement learning Q
learning update um and the reinforcement
learning Decay and Epsilon control Decay
Epsilon so um here in the evaluation um
definition um we are evaluating the
agent's performance on the provided
evaluation data uh that's provided by
The Arc and this just gives a baseline
for is my model actually solving the
tasks or is it am I just we off base I
mean there has to be um uh some uh which
is I'm so grateful for them for thinking
of this and and the the way that they've
structured everything even if it's the
hardest thing you've ever done is still
absolutely brilliant and uh intentional
and uh and it's so easy to see the
wisdom of it once you get into it um
they have you know given us the ability
to you know create a baseline for oh
okay these systems work these solve
tasks um but will it solve you you know
uh the test so we'll see um the uh these
are just a lot of uh if that then this
kind of things um if error then uh kind
of stuff um and then we get down to the
main execution block one thing I want to
be clear about the there are there is
only a small small fraction of the
cognitive mechanisms that just I by
myself have uh made that have proven
effective in other ways and in different
systemss and for different purposes um
and I'd really like to encourage other
people um who are interested to uh
really dig in and explore the
possibilities there because not only is
active inference um amazing and
Incredibly incredibly challenging um but
the potentials for discoveries it's like
there's something around every corner
under every Rock every single equation
that um you come across to hold some
hidden and deeper meaning it's almost
esoteric and when we when I'm putting
them together and seeing how they
interoperate um there are things that
that become evident or obvious um that
can be like with the confidence and the
Decay Factor um that uh we put into
introduce humility uh where they can be
silly kind of and fun and just
thoughtful or they can be something
that's deeply meaningful and deeply
impactful um and has broad reaching uh
technological implications uh for
Humanity um such as Robert warden's
requirement equation for cognition um
and uh this is all just a boring stuff
here this is um where we're initializing
that uh problemsolving intelligence um
we're plotting metrics we're calling uh
the test files so the Json formatted
files that contain the uh training
challenges and training uh Solutions
yada yada so um I don't spend a lot of
time looking at those things um uh
because I want to uh kind of maintain uh
the um the veracity like I really want
the model to work uh on its own and to
do all of the heavy lifting I don't want
to bias the model by knowing too much
about how the competition even works
which is uh made some things certainly
more difficult for me than others um but
uh overall it's like I wouldn't have
traded this experience for uh anything
and Daniel I'm so grateful to you for um
tasking me with this um definitely um
the things that you've always uh given
me to do uh and as undertakings are uh I
there are things that I don't even think
I didn't even know I didn't I could do
and this is one of those things that's
just been an absolutely transformative
experience that has radically increased
uh my abilities and um has given me so
much Insight uh that uh that has like
inspired my curiosity and it's like I
can't wait to research and read more and
put pen to paper and and uh continue uh
coding I never thought I would be doing
that so um this as you can see is the
kagle working submission. Json this is
what I have been pulling my hair out
over uh forever not this necessarily
this file path but actually generating
this file path this has always been
there since the beginning but this file
path would not uh create and this is
like for instance um when tearing my
model apart to make this which U
unfortunately some of the cool pieces
that belong uh as Integrations here were
not in this um because I had to uh
figure out what was preventing that
submission file from being generated and
it was U turned out a bunch of things
just my lack of uh familiarity with
coding I'm not an expert so um though I
maybe if I keep up at it uh someday so
the um there were things inside and
outside of loops and I found uh some
functions that had uh basically been
rendered uh ineffectual um as a result
in those failures in the system uh were
stopping the formation of the of the
Json file uh pathway before it could uh
it could be enacted so um here if and I
don't know if anybody's interested in
this um uh I can I'll quickly scroll
down to the bottom and we'll see I don't
know if this is one of the um it may
take a second to uh so let me leave this
alone uh but
here um let me try the logs so here uh
in for instance uh this is Archangel
1.0 uh it successfully ran in
3,163 seconds uh which is actually
pretty slow um I don't know what the
other people's like what other
competitors code looks like um certainly
um uh the um and just let me know if my
screen starts lagging um it usually does
when this starts running um but uh I
know that they're brilliant they're
experts every single one of them and um
their models will typically run really
fast uh and are very I'm assuming very
very very efficient I know I'm assuming
probably an under when I first started
um before I I really got the cognitive
mechanisms in play um in those somatic
subsystems and um some of those larger
uh calculations that are occurring um
the uh the model would complete almost
instantaneously it was just so quick um
the blink of an eye and 1,200 uh
questions training all of that gone and
producing a result um but the result was
not fav able it wasn't uh a score that I
would be happy with Daniel I don't I if
I remember correctly Daniel didn't ask
me to um uh get first place he asked me
to beat the theoretical maximum uh so
that's what I'm trying to do so here you
can see where it says uh does not exist
I was so sad um but let me see if we can
get uh uh if there is any scoring to be
had uh no um so unfortunately uh I
picked the one model
um didn't produce a score uh because I
was tearing it apart to U find that
submission file which we'll see no op uh
no operation none um in the submission
file you have you can submit uh my model
only produces one output one correct
answer but you can actually choose uh to
produce two if you want like you can get
two tries and getting the answer right
that's how hard the test is um so my
model uh
was um there the basically the action
selection through a boring series of
events um in the generate action space
was uh was not selecting a new action
and so uh it was defaulting to the air
of uh no operation and uh closing the
task out completely so in this case the
tasks were being prematurely uh ended or
were running uh as no operation through
their total iterations which in this
case it looks like it was set to 500 so
um I would love to um if I can I don't
know if I'll be able to but certainly
anybody can uh reach out to me directly
um as those log files uh are I download
them every time and uh uh you can see
that score of uh of 86.4% consistently
uh about 84 or 86 uh above 86 to 87%
what's really interesting is it seems
that I'm GNA have to just get out of
this uh and because it's a my sounds
like my computer's firing up like a jet
engine so the um I wonder and I would
love other people's thoughts on this um
if um if there is necessarily there if
you cannot get
100% um no matter at like I have seemed
to like kind of and it may just me but
unless I gain the system there's not
really a way to get a higher score the
system naturally even scoring well above
the the the maximum uh
possible um still won't get every answer
right so uh I don't know if that's uh
because it has to be that way or if it's
uh if it's just my uh my lack of uh
familiarity um with this so um I'm going
to try one more time really quickly to
um
uh uh I don't want to there we go um to
find oh here we go that's not it should
be right here
the huh yeah must still be
running no graft session
oh here we
are so one of the things that's uh also
been uh fascinating is learning all of
the new systems all of the time um and
uh it's like every day I have to learn a
new system and it's it's pretty amazing
it's keeps you on your toes that's for
sure so let me edit the oh wait no here
logs oh
no let see if this pops up really quick
thank you everybody for your patience I
appreciate
it here we are let me see we should have
Yep this model
complete be able to see that either if
it's not going to um
yeah I'm sorry guys I I don't want to
waste uh too much uh I don't want to
waste like people's time uh
unnecessarily I know everybody is uh how
about go show the low road high road and
then we'll see if there's any last
questions and that we'll be good for it
oh okay low road High Road um I'm trying
to think whereas uh I I don't know if I
I I'm so disorganized after the uh
having like okay okay it's all all good
that all good I don't know where it is
okay then you can unshare that can be
basically the end how is it going to
continue from here so um I I have to
kind of rebuild the model back up um and
uh but I'm very confident uh based on
the model's performance um that uh once
the pro like everything's integrated
because that's another thing the mo
these models if they're not the they
don't just kind of like gradually get
the questions or they'll get like 80%
one time and 20% another time um it
seems for me at least um that there is a
a you you're either getting in the
you're either getting like
70% with this framework or you're
getting 0o per. like it has to the there
are specific criteria almost whereby the
model will be able to uh perform better
but it's either better or really not at
all each framework for instance the the
model that is producing like Archangel
1.0 that
produces uh uh the
86% uh consistent score right is not the
same model in any way as the model that
uh that I first started with that would
only produce 30% and the model that
produced 48% the model that produced 72%
right they're all different and
structured differently and each one has
been um trial and error 100% And
and hundreds of hours in the last month
and a half I'm like 700 hours in
somebody said told me that my the bags
under my eyes were going into my cheeks
like they
was so I thought that was pretty
funny okay do you have any last comments
or
ideas um no I I I think that cognitive
Computing is so exciting um that active
inference is so exciting there's so much
room for Discovery here there's so much
room for creativity everything that
again that we see and we find is is
inspiring in every way and the
implications for the how those
Technologies are employed um has broad
and very very very important uh uh like
implications for Humanity I think I I
think it's like the next big thing
all right thank you Benjamin good luck
with getting the submission and I hope
that you can reduce people's uncertainty
which will surely be the realized
efficacy of your scripts oh well thank
you thank you bye